本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 粟  Miss无语  jimbert  莫若谦  猴三儿
校对|后期： 莫若谦
以下是你上星期错过的《无耻之徒》
This is what you missed last week on Shameless.
我的宝贝
My baby!
真爱
True love.
嘿 帅哥
Hey, hot stuff.
- 你从事什么职业 - 房地产 我住在迈阿密
- What do you do? - Real estate. I live in Miami.
- 我把利普踢走了 - 他去哪儿了
- I kicked Lip out. - Where'd he go?
我可以在你家住一晚吗
Is it all right if I stay over tonight?
- 看到吉米是不是很奇怪 - 吉米是谁
- Was it weird seeing Jimmy? - Who's Jimmy?
吉米就是史蒂夫
Jimmy is Steve.
我勒个去 那我能在星期五见到这个小家伙了
Holy shit. I'm gonna see the little guy on Friday?
是啊 就一小会
Yep. For, like, a second.
我的天 这小混蛋是要了我的命啊
Christ almighty! This cocksucker's killing me!
当他们好上的时候 那是真的好
When they're good, they're good.
只有你真正理解我
You're the only one who truly understands me.
她哪儿不对劲吗 她躺在床上好几天了
Is something wrong with her? She hasn't gotten out of bed in days.
莫妮卡有双向情绪障碍 小黛比
Monica's bipolar, Debs.
是时候让你重新吃药了 是吗
Time for you to go back on your meds, huh?
- 我操 - 什么事
- Holy fuck. - What happened?
- 妈妈 妈妈 - 天啊 这发生了意外
- Mommy, Mommy... - Oh, God, there's been an accident.
- 她留了很多血 他们在路上了 - 你跟着我
- She's bleeding badly. They're on their way. - You with me?
没事的 没事的 跟着我
It's gonna be okay. We're good, we're good. Stay with me.
- 她怎么样了 - 她稳定了
- How is she? - She's stable.
你们都回家吧
You should go home.
- 利普刚打了电话 - 他来吗
- Lip just called. - He's coming?
- 凯伦在楼上生孩子 - 我操
- Karen's having a baby upstairs. - Holy fuck!
快出来了
It's coming, it's coming!
他有什么不对劲吗
What's wrong with him?
- 他有唐氏综合症 小黛比 - 我操 凯伦
- He's has Downs Syndrome, Debs. - What the fuck, Karen?
我从来没说过是你的孩子
I never said it was your baby.
我拿到宝宝了
I got the baby, I got the baby!
快上来
Come on, come on!
我拿到宝宝了
I've got a baby!
无耻之徒 第二季第12集
# 回想你所得到的运气 #
think of all the luck you got
# 你并不是命途多舛 #
know that it's not for naught
# 你曾笑容满面 #
you were beaming once before
# 但已不曾再现 #
but it's not like that anymore
# 你曾经的落魄 #
what is this downside
# 何以形容 #
that you speak of?
# 你如此肯定的 #
what is this feeling
# 是什么样的感受 #
you're so sure of?
# 召集你所有的朋友 #
round up the friends you got
# 你并不是孤身一人 #
know that they're not for naught
# 你曾心甘付出 #
you were willing once before
# 但已不曾再现 #
but it's not like that anymore
# 曾经的落魄 #
what is this downside
# 何以形容 #
that you speak of?
# 你如此肯定的 #
what is this feeling
# 是什么样的 #
you're so...
# 感受 #
sure of?
莫妮卡
Monica!
Monica?
莫妮卡
Monica!
莫妮卡简 盖拉格
Monica Jean Gallagher!
莫妮卡
Monica!
天啊
Oh, God.
操
Oh, shit.
天啊
Oh, God...
老天
Jesus.
党卫军
Schutzstaffel.
你在做什么呢
What the hell are you doing?
你偷了我老婆
You stole my wife!
什么
What?
你偷了我老婆 我要把她找回来
You stole my wife, and I want her back.
好吧 探望时间是早上九点到下午四点
Okay, visiting hours are 9:00 to 4:00.
你要是想见她 就到时候再来
You want to see her, come back then.
- 出来莫妮卡- 嘿
- Come out, Monica! - Hey!
快滚
Get out of here.
莫妮卡回家
Monica, come home!
我爱你
I love you!
我永远不会离开你
I'll never leave you!
永远不会
Never...
你是天使
You're an angel.
保佑
A blessing.
上天保佑
My little Kung Pow blessing.
嗯 要想办法把这个防盗的东西摘下来
Hmm. Gotta figure out how to get this security thing off.
你这个漂亮的
What a big, beautiful,
熊猫娃娃
panda-Pooh Bear boy you are.
看
Oh, look.
他这儿还有包皮
He's still got his little dingy-ding skin.
我们要帮他割掉吗
Should we get him circumcised?
当然不 就让龟头自己长出来
Hell, no. Let that extra derma ride.
我们要给他起名字
Oh, he needs a name.
希拉姆怎么样 和我爸爸一样
What about Hiram, for my father?
你是小希吗
Are you a Hymmie?
他们可能会追踪这个东西 就像婴儿防盗
Hmm. Think they can track this thing, like a baby LoJack?
你是小小希吗
Are you a little Hymmie?
- 亲爱的小希 - 他的名字应该更像中国人一点
- A Hymmie-wymie? - The name should be something Chinese.
- 能让他和同种族的人亲近些 - 嗯
- Keep him connected to his people. - Hmm.
中国式...
Chinese...
陈陈
Chen, Chan,
张
Chang...
温 王
Wing? Wang?
- 吴- 哎... 这个太紧了
- Wu? - Hm... it's pretty tight.
我怕不小心把他的脚也割掉了
I don't want to slip and cut his leg off.
你可以同时解开他的脚镯
Well, you could clip his ankle bracelet
和包皮
and his foreskin at the same time.
我朋友辛迪重新回去工作了
Hey, my friend Cindy went back to work.
可以挤奶 五块一次
Has to pump. For a five-spot,
应该可以问她要新鲜的人奶
I bet she'd hook us up with some breast milk.
他们要来找他
They're going to be looking for him.
- 我们要把他藏起来 - 阁楼可以吗
- We need to hide him. - How about the attic?
就像电影里那个希伯来女孩
Like that movie about the Hebrew girl.
不行 冬天的时候会很冷 地下室怎么样
No, it gets cold in the winter. What about the basement?
不行 他们第一时间要到那儿找 亲爱的
No, it's the first place they'll look, sweetie.
干衣机
Dryer?
但要记住他在里面
Just can't forget he's in there.
嗯
Right.
我去整理桌子
I'll clear the table.
小黛比 该睡觉了
Debs, bedtime.
该死的
Fuck.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
可怜的孩子们
These poor kids.
别担心 他们已经很糟糕了
Don't worry, they're already pretty fucked up.
我是说...
I mean...
没事 呼吸
Okay, you can breathe.
保持呼吸
Keep breathing.
你没事吧
You gonna be all right?
菲奥娜 我...
Fiona, I...
# 直至如今我应知道 #
I should know
# 我是谁 #
Who I am by now
# 我走着 #
I walk
# 设法所记录的 #
The record stands somehow
# 是冬天的怀念 #
Thinking of winter
# 你的名字分裂着我的内心 #
Your name is the splinter inside me
# 当我等待时 #
While I wait
# 我记起的声音 #
And I remember the sound
# 十一月市中心有你的热闹 #
Of your November downtown
# 我记起的真相 #
And I remember the truth
# 温暖的十二月有你陪伴 #
A warm December with you
# 但我无须犯错 #
But I don't have to make this mistake
# 更无须停滞不前 #
And I don't have to stay this way
# 但愿我可以等待 #
If only I would wait
# 人行道已空无一人 #
The walk has all been cleared by now
# 我只听见你的声音 #
Your voice is all I hear somehow
# 在呼喊冬天 #
Calling out, winter
# 你的声音分裂着我的内心 #
Your voice is the splinter inside me
# 在我等待的时候 #
While I wait
菲奥娜
Fiona?
# 我所记起的声音 #
I remember the sound
进来吧
Yeah, come on in.
你没睡
You awake?
嗯
Yeah.
# 还有我记起的真相 #
And I remember the truth
# 温暖的十二月有你陪伴 #
A warm December with you
# 但我无须犯错 #
But I don't have to make this mistake
# 更无须停滞不前 #
And I don't have to stay this way
# 但愿我会等待 #
If only I would wait
# 在困难中迷失自己 #
I could have lost myself in rough
没事了
Shh. It's okay.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
# 我记起的声音 #
I remember the sound
# 十一月市中心有你的热闹 #
Of your November downtown...
有人把宝宝偷走了
Somebody stole the baby.
他们认为是我的妈妈
They think it was my mom.
天啊
Jesus.
你叫了警察
You call the police?
她估计就是和平时一样吓到
She probably just freaked out, like always.
我打算拿回来
I'm gonna get it back.
或许你应该让你妈妈带他一段时间
Well, maybe you should let your mom keep him for awhile.
至少直到你确定
You know, at least till you're sure
你不会改变主意了
you're not gonna change your mind.
我不会改变主意了
I'm not gonna change my mind.
嗯 可是你没想好呢吧 你可以
Yeah, but you don't know that. I mean, you could really...
我才不要碰那个东西呢 好不好
I don't want that fucking thing anywhere near me, okay?
去问问我什么时候能离开这鬼地方
Go ask somebody when I can get the hell out of here.
我想赶去吃温迪快餐店的早餐
I want to hit Wendy's before they stop serving breakfast.
早上好
Morning.
孩子们还睡着呢
Kids still sleeping?
呃 对呀
Uh, yeah.
火鸡加鸡蛋
Turkey and eggs?
还有碎土豆香饼
With mashed potato pancakes
- 还有蔓越莓果酱 - 嗯
- and cranberry jelly. - Hmm.
你又是这里的常住居民啦 史蒂夫
You back to being a legal resident around here, Steve?
吉米 他现在是吉米了
Jimmy. His name's Jimmy now.
史蒂夫只是他以前对我
Steve was just an alias he used
隐瞒身份的时候用的化名
to lie to me about who he really was.
噢 不太好哦 吉米-史蒂夫
Ooh, not cool, Jimmy-Steve.
- 要鸡蛋不 - 我要拿着走
- Eggs? - To go.
我改名是因为当时
I changed my name 'cause I was
我在偷卡 万一出了什么事
stealing cars. Didn't want anyone to
我可不想被查出来
be able to track me down if things went south.
跟你可没有任何关系
It didn't have anything to do with you.
当然
Yeah.
我想见见你的家人
I want to meet your family.
不 你可不会想见他们
Oh, no, you don't.
我想啊
Yes, I do.
他们就是一群可悲的人
They're miserable people.
龌龊又自大的混蛋
Nasty, egomaniacal shit-heads.
- 全都是那样 - 嗯 我妈还行
- All of them? - Yeah, Mom's okay
我指的是她把酒喝足了的时候
when she's knocked back enough Chardonnay.
你家有几个人
How many of you are there?
呃 我妈 我爸 一个超级混蛋
Uh, Mom, Dad-- shit-head superstar.
哥哥奇普
Older brother Chip--
准超级混蛋
shit-head superstar-in-training.
好想见他们哦
Can't wait to meet them.
你肯定会失望的
You're going to be disappointed.
反正我又不是没失望过
Wouldn't be the first time someone's disappointed me.
那好吧
Okay.
你今天真漂亮
You look beautiful.
你骗人
Liar.
他们对你怎么样
So, you getting okay care here?
药很极品
Good drugs?
你需要什么东西吗
You need anything?
呃 烟 洗发露 钢锯
Uh, cigarettes, shampoo, hacksaw?
衣服
Clothes.
我的衣服一团糟
Mine are a mess.
我会拿点过来的
I'll bring by some stuff.
我把感恩节给搞砸了
I really screwed up Thanksgiving.
没有啊 不是什么大事
No, it was no big deal.
孩子们
The kids?
肯定吓死了吧
I must have scared the shit out of them.
他们好着呢
They're good.
我们昨晚谈了一下
We, uh, talked it out last night,
然后我帮他们盖好被子 他们今天好得很
and I tucked them in, they're fine today.
你才不会哄他们上床睡觉呢
You didn't tuck them in.
反正我给他们读了书 小故事
I read books to them, the little ones, anyway.
你马上就可以出去了
You'll be out soon.
你自己也知道的
You'll see for yourself.
快不了
Not soon.
七十二小时
72 hours.
已经过了十五小时了
You already got 15 under your belt.
我要求再待六十天
I signed myself in for 60 more days.
自愿的
Voluntary commitment.
啊 快告诉我你要改主意
Well, tell them you changed your mind.
不行啊
I can't.
这是说好的
That's part of the deal.
弗兰克 我得让自己正常起来
Frank, I got to get myself normal.
我不能再这样了 对他们不公平
I can't keep doing this to them.
你就是有一点忧郁而已
You're just a little blue.
所有人都可能会有这种问题
It happens to everyone every now and again.
我可以在家照顾你
I can take care of you at home.
你不能啊
No, you can't.
我爱你啊
I love you.
你应该跟我们在一起
You belong with us.
我
I'm...
我要待在我应该待的地方 好吗
I'm where I need to be, okay?
我得走了
I got to go.
我有个小组
I got group.
给借我点可卡因吗
Can I borrow a cup of cocaine?
- 没啦 - 咖啡
- All out. - Coffee?
孩子们今天早上怎么样
How are the little ones this morning?
昨天晚上看到妈妈割腕
After seeing their mother slit her wrists?
精神受创
Traumatized.
应该有些团体专门帮助受过这种伤害的孩子啊
Has to be support groups for kids who've seen shit like that.
对 他们把一半的同学杀光之后
Yeah, in maximum security prisons
到了大型监狱里就肯定有了
after they've mowed down half their classmates.
你让史蒂夫在这儿过夜了啊
You let Steve spend the night?
你是说吉米
You mean Jimmy?
去你的 我就叫他史蒂夫
Fuck that, I'm calling him Steve.
我让他去完成一个任务
I sent him out on a quest.
嗯 让他夺回某处女的心
Mm! Making him re-win the heart of the virgin?
天啊 V
Christ, V,
我可不能让他在掺进这团乱麻里
I can't let him back into this madness.
不是他自己选的吗
Isn't that his choice?
呃 他现在觉得他想这样
Well, he thinks he wants it now,
但是一两年之后呢
but just wait a year or two.
等我怀孕了 半夜里弗兰克在我们
When I have one in the oven and Frank throws up in our bed
床上吐一下 或者莫妮卡想在
in the middle of the night or Monica tries
衣柜里用破鞋带上吊自杀
to hang herself in a closet with an old shoelace.
他也不是孩子啦 让他自己决定吧
He's a big boy, he can make his own decisions.
嘿 卡尔
Hey, Carl.
睡得好吗
Sleep okay?
你说呢
What do you think?
饿了吗
You hungry?
- 我给你做个三明治吧 - 好
- Let me make you a sandwich. - Okay.
残障调查的人
Disability check
下星期才来 弗兰克
doesn't come for another week, Frank.
今天早上我去医院看了看你妈
I went to visit your mother in the hospital this morning.
我们得把她弄出来
We have to get her out of there.
那就是她应该呆的地方
Best place for her.
- 她很脆弱 - 她不正常
- She's fragile. - She's broken.
他们想把她搞正常
They want to make her normal.
他们是想帮她
They want to help her.
正常的意思就是成为平庸 了无生趣的
By which they mean average, boring, medicated,
药罐子莫妮卡
a Stepford Monica.
她昨晚可是想自杀啊
She tried to kill herself last night;
没趣都是求之不得的了
boring would be a blessing.
他们现在会做脑叶切除术
They perform lobotomies now.
才不是呢
No, they don't.
- 电击治疗 - 没这回事
- Shock treatment? - No.
其实 我觉得有吧 莉亚公主就试过啊
Actually, I think they do. Princess Leia did it.
100,000伏的电
100,000 volts of electricity
穿过她的头颅
zapped into her skull!
要用好多的能量 整个城市都得停电
Draws so much power, it takes out entire city blocks.
我们的灯变暗的时候
When our lights dim, some poor fucker's
可怜虫们正在被人烧脑子呢
getting his brains fried.
别听他的 卡尔
Don't listen to him, Carl.
吃你的早餐吧
Eat your breakfast.
脑叶切除是什么
What's a lobotomy?
他们把一个东西塞进你脑子里
They jam a screwdriver
然后使劲乱绞
into your head and scramble your brains.
才不是这样的 哎呀 弗兰克
No, they don't. Jesus, Frank.
- 是真的啊 - 他们会让妈继续
- Yeah, they do! - They're gonna put Mom
吃药 会让她好起来的
back on her meds. They're gonna make her better.
吃药对她可没好处
She's not better on her meds.
她就是个空壳 她把生命里所爱的一切都丢掉了
She's a zombie. She gives up everything she loves in life.
哦 丢掉了什么 毒品 酒精 你
Yeah, like what? Drugs, alcohol, you?
我们
Us.
在他们把她变得不像她之前
I'm gonna bust her out of there
我要把她弄出来
before they steal what makes Monica Monica.
你到底支不支持我
Are you with me?
就让她呆在那里吧 弗兰克
Leave her alone, Frank.
她需要抓住机会好起来
She needs a chance to get well.
别人能把你变成其他人
Somebody can steal what makes you you?
不能 卡尔
No. Carl?
他也不站在你这边
He's not helping you, either.
我能拿上我的Mac-10手枪吗
Can I bring my Mac-10 pistol?
别把他扯进去 枪你得交给
Leave him out of this. The pistol's going back
- 警察 - 你姐姐呢
- to the cops. - Where's your sister?
洗澡呢
Shower.
- 别拉上黛比 弗兰克 - 不
- Leave Debbie alone, Frank! - No.
莫妮卡如果从医院出来以后会好很多的 卡尔
Monica will be better when she comes out of the hospital, Carl.
我通过了
I passed.
学业考试 我通过了
The GED-- I passed.
老爸
Daddy!
老爸 你应该敲门的啊
Daddy, you're supposed to knock!
你爱不爱你妈妈
Do you love your mother?
辛迪说这东西是给那些不能
Cindy says they make this thing for women who can't produce
产奶的女性做的
their own milk.
把这玩意儿挂在脖子上
You hang this doohickey around your neck,
然后把这些
and then you tape these right over
贴在乳头上
your nipples.
这样就可以"母乳喂养"婴儿了
And the baby can still breast-feed.
算了吧 亲爱的 我能搞定
It's okay, honey, I-I can do it.
不是啊 我们两个人都得和他有亲密的关系 很重要的
No, it's important for both of us to bond with him.
好吧
Okay.
好
来吧 孩子
There, sweet boy.
真是 啊
That's... Whoa.
现在我可体会到这种感觉了
Now I know what all the fuss is about.
有人来了
Someone's here. Oh.
妈
Mom?
Mom.
亲爱的
Sweetie!
天啊 这么快就回来啦
My goodness! Home already?
医院让你走了吗
Did the hospital let you leave?
它在哪里
Where is it?
他们不是至少得让你
Thought they usually like to keep you
- 多呆几天吗 - 它在哪里啊 妈
- for at least a day. - Where is it, Mom?
什么在哪里 宝贝
Where's what, honey?
它
It.
昨晚用大脑袋在我身体里
The baby that shoved its ginormous head
挤来挤去挤了六个小时的那个婴儿
out of my cooter for six endless hours last night.
哇 他们把他给弄丢了
Oh, my. Did they lose it?
他们给我看了个录像 是你拿走了
They showed me the video footage of you taking it.
- 哦 那个小孩啊 - 他们本来想报警的
- Oh, that baby. - They were gonna call
我说算了
the police, but I said no.
它在哪儿
Where is it?
- 快说啊 妈 - 在烘干机里
- Now, Mom! - In the dryer.
拿出来
Take it out.
他好像还在午睡
I think he's napping.
快拿出来
Take it out!
我不想碰那东西
I don't want to touch it!
你在漏奶
You're leaking.
多漂亮的孩子
Isn't he beautiful?
送它回医院吧
Take it back to the hospital.
会有人想要它的
Somebody will want it.
我要它
I want it.
我不答应
Well, you can't have it.
他是个特别乖的宝宝
He's such a sweet boy.
从不哭闹
He never cries.
长得又漂亮
He's so handsome.
我们想给他起你祖父的名字
We want to name him Hiram
叫他希拉姆
after your grandfather.
或者叫明 让他保持中国特色
Or maybe Ming, to keep him wired into his Chinese-ness.
乔迪你闭嘴
Shut up, Jody.
必须送它回去
It's going back.
凯伦 别这样
Karen, please don't do this.
随便他们把它送去哪儿 弱智呆的疯人院之类的
They'll give it to the retarded freaks' home or whatever.
他是我的外孙
He's my grandson.
我不会让你像扔掉张废纸一样
I won't let you throw him away
扔掉他的
like used Kleenex.
凯伦 或许你妈妈说的没错
You know, Karen, your mom might be right.
是该让她养一段日子
Maybe she should keep him for a while.
谁知道
You know, who knows
社工们会对他做些什么
what social services is going to do with him?
没你的事儿 利普
Butt out, Lip!
你呆这儿是想干嘛
What are you even doing here?
他都不是你的种
He's not even yours.
这事儿和你半毛钱关系都没有
This is none of your goddamn business.
至少给蒂姆王或者别的谁的那个爹打个电话
At least call Tim Wong or whoever the father is
告诉他一声
and tell him about it.
滚
Get out!
你被这娘们甩了
You dodged a fucking RPG
那才真是走大运了
getting tossed over by this one.
可不是吗 哥们
Don't I know it, man.
送它回医院
Take it back to the hospital.
要是医院不收怎么办
What if they won't take it back?
那就放篮子里
Then drop it in a basket
扔消防队门口
and leave it at the fire station.
我不在乎
I don't give a shit.
不
No.
不要
就要
Yes!
他就留在我身边
He is staying with me.
行啊
Fine!
那我就去报警了
Then I'm calling the police.
利普在吗
Lip here?
利普
Lip!
是你姐
It's your sister.
话说
So...
你怎么找到我的
How'd you find me?
吉米说的
Jimmy.
凯伦怎么样了
How's Karen?
那娘们真是个贱人
Girl's a fucking bitch.
我表亲 叫艾丽
My cousin, Eli, was born
出生的时候一个脚丫长膝盖上
with a foot coming out of his knee.
现在他是个铁匠
Now he's a blacksmith.
使起风箱来都不带用手拉的
Only one who can pump the bellows
比谁都牛
without using his hands.
我自考过了
I passed my GED.
别一脸不相信的样子
Don't look so surprised.
我没有
No, I'm not.
那真是 真是太好了
That's, um...that's great.
说好的不能不算
So... deal's a deal.
太迟了
Ah, too late.
- 覆水难收了 - 我过了考试
- Spilt milk. - I passed.
- 你就回去念书 - 泼出去的水了
- You go back to school. - Water under the bridge.
少来这套
Knock off the clichés.
过了这个村了
Road not taken.
我希望你能回家 利普
I want you home, Lip.
大家都是
We all do.
好吧
Right.
那里只有冷水 还不让睡觉
It's cold water and sleep deprivation.
在生殖器上缠上电极
Make you stand all day
一站就是一整天
with electrodes tied to your genitals.
我觉得你说的不像是县医院 倒像是阿比格莱比监狱
I think you're mistaking Cook County for Abi Grabie.
- 是阿布格莱底 - 阿布格莱布
- Abu Gradie. - Abu Ghraib.
伊拉克监狱 曾出过美军虐囚丑闻
有个守卫带我去绕过一圈 在巴士拉那会儿
Did a tour with the Guard-- Basra.
他们不虐囚 弗兰克
They don't do any of that, Frank.
我去年上那儿呆过
I was in there last year
就是我不当心嗑药过量那次
after my accidental overdose.
不当心 你那次吸可卡因的时候都把自己给点着了
Accidental? You set yourself on fire freebasing.
基本上就是大家坐成一圈
It was mostly us sitting in a circle
说说自己是怎么被
in a group talking about how your family
- 家人毁了的 - 莫妮卡聊起弗兰克
- screwed you up. -  Oh, Monica talking about Frank?
可是得花上一会儿
That ought to take a while.
弗兰克 你带钱了吗
Frank, you got any cash?
钞票 票子
Moolah? Green?
我必须把她从那儿弄出来
I got to spring her out of there.
我俩就像阴阳两仪
She's the yin to my yang.
她就是我苏打水里的威士忌
She's the scotch in my soda.
我俩就是金姐与弗雷 [美国舞王舞后]
We are Fred and Ginger.
列侬和洋子 米奇和米妮
John and Yoko. Mickey and Minnie.
更像是席格菲与洛依
More like Siegfried and Roy.
希特勒和艾娃
Adolf and Eva.
你儿子还是在医院上晚班吗 汤米
Your boy still working nights at the hospital, Tommy?
是啊 支持服务技术员
Support services technician, yeah.
支持服务技术员 不就是个清洁工吗
Support services technician? I thought he was a janitor.
不管怎样是个工作
A job's a job.
至少帕特有工作
At least Pat's got one.
帕蒂几点上班
What time's Patty go to work?
晚上都安排好了
We're on for tonight.
- 晚上怎么了 - 要和我家人吃饭啊
- What's tonight? - Dinner with my family.
你要求的 我实现了
You asked, you got it.
他们上这儿来吗
Are they coming here?
呃 不是
Uh... no.
我爸有日子没离开过市区了
Dad hasn't been south of the Art Institute Gala
最近一次还是84年比利・乔尔在科米斯基公园开演唱会那次
since Billy Joel played Comiskey Park in '84.
- 那去他们家 - 也不是
- Going to their house for dinner? - Nope.
我妈可能要先给你除个虱才行
Uh, Mom would have to have you deloused first.
她有洁癖
She's a germophobe.
要想从碟子里拿颗杏仁
You want an almond out of the serving dish,
你得带上医用手套拿手术钳夹
you have to wear surgical gloves and use tongs.
我见过你妈
I met your mom.
她 她还可以
She's... she's cool.
你见过他妈
You met his mom?
坎黛丝
Candace.
肉毒打的有点过量
A little heavy on the Botox
香奈儿五号也撒的有点重 但人不错
and Chanel No. 5, but nice.
那我们上哪儿见面
So where are we meeting?
去市区的莫顿那
Uh, Morton's, downtown.
我爸在那家有个酒柜
Dad has a wine locker there.
就是黄铜铭牌上
Little brass plaque
刻着他的名字的那种
with his name on it and everything.
- 大家都去 - 是的 我爸请客
- Everybody invited? - Yep. Dad's buying,
所以挑菜单上
so order the most expensive thing
- 最贵的点 - 上肋牛排
- on the menu. - Prime rib?
- 没问题 - 那带骨上腰牛排呢
- Sure. - Bone-in porterhouse steak?
什么都行 你去吗 小黛比 去蹭饭
Anything you want. What do you say, Debs, free meal?
去不了 吉姆 我忙着呢
No can do, Jim. Busy.
- 忙着干嘛 - 去霍莉・哈克米尔家夜宿
- Doing what? - Sleeping over at Holly Herkimier's.
别跟着她学坏了
Don't do anything she does.
超大的龙虾呢
Big-ass lobster?
当然
You bet.
# 扭曲的心灵 #
Bad, bad heart
# 扭曲的想法 #
Bad, bad mind
# 时刻想着 #
Thinking bad thoughts
# 扭曲的想法 #
All the time
# 早晨醒来 #
Waking up in the morning...
我嘞个去
Jesus Christ!
你都不冲洗这些东西的吗
Don't you ever hose these things out?
比死掉妓女的后庭还要难闻
Smells worse than a dead hooker's ass in there.
轻点声行吗
Keep your voice down, all right?
慢点儿 帅哥
Easy, cowboy.
那颗橘黄的 那可是专业级的
That orange one's for experts only.
要是你被逮了
Hey, you do get caught,
不许供出我来 听见没
you never heard of me, all right?
你在里面还好吗 亲爱的
Doing good in there, pumpkin?
嗯哼 很好 爸爸
Mm-hmm. A-okay, Daddy.
- 警察来了 - 啊
- Cops! - Aah!
- 快点 妈妈 赶紧的 - 好的
- Come on, Mom. Hurry up. - Okay.
- 我正快着呢 - 快点啊妈
- I'm hurrying. Okay! - Mom, come on!
妈 警察来了啊
Police are here, Mom.
杰克逊夫人 你好啊
Hello, Mrs. Jackson.
你好
Hey.
托尼 你妈妈还好吗
Tony. How's your mom?
- 糖尿病还是不见好啊 - 是的 女士
- The diabetes still giving her fits? - Yes, ma'am.
夏天的时候掉了两根脚趾 但是她还顶得住
Lost two toes over the summer, but she's hanging tough.
必须的啊
Well, she'd have to be--
这么多年来一直溜冰的结果啊
all those years skating with the Ice Capades.
我们接到绑架的举报
Uh... we got a call about a kidnapping.
我妈和乔迪
Oh... Mom and Jody
把我的孩子从医院偷了出来
stole my baby from the hospital.
你生了
You had your baby?
恭喜啊
Congratulations.
谢谢 像是经历了场恐怖片似的 但是
Thanks. It was a fucking horror show, but I...
总算生下了这鬼玩意儿
finally had the damn thing.
他们偷了孩子出来 现在我想让你们送回去
They stole it, and I want you to take it back.
你 你不想留下孩子吗
You don't... want to keep the baby?
他是个智障
It's retarded.
我想让它回医院 好让医院送它去
I want it to go back so they can give it away
那些关心唐氏综合症宝宝的人家
to the Down Syndrome baby do-gooders
或是送给郡政府之类的
or the county or whatever.
纠正一下你对唐氏儿童的表述
Correct term for Downs kids
是发育不健全
is "developmentally delayed."
不管怎样 我妈和她发育不健全的男友
Well, my baby was stolen by my mom
偷了我的孩子
and her developmentally delayed boyfriend.
- 他不是我男友 - 我不是
- He's not my boyfriend. - I'm not?
呃 杰克逊夫人
Uh, Mrs. Jackson,
你确实抱走了你女儿的孩子吗
did you take your daughter's baby?
孩子 什么孩子
Baby? What baby?
夫人 孩子是在洗衣篮里吗
Ma'am, is the baby in the laundry basket?
是的
Yes.
交给警察吧 妈
Give it to the cop, Mom.
凯伦亲爱的 求你了 别这样
Karen, honey, please don't do this.
快看
Ah, man.
多漂亮的宝宝啊
Look how handsome you are.
是吧 是的
Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
快把孩子交给警察 妈
Give it to the damn cop, Mom!
她是你妈妈
So this is your mother,
她想要照看这个孩子
and she wants to take care of the baby?
是的 但是我不想把他留下来
Yes, but I don't want it here.
那你是想要一个完全陌生的人来带走他
And you want a total stranger to take him
或是让伊利诺伊斯州
or the State of Illinois to be responsible for him
用纳税人的钱来养他
on the taxpayers' dime?
你饿了吗 我想吃泰国菜
You hungry? I'm thinking Thai.
好的
Yeah.
就这样 你们就这么走了
That's it? You're just gonna leave?
很高兴见到你 杰克逊太太
Nice seeing you, Mrs. Jackson.
- 我会向我妈转达您的问候 - 多谢
-I'll tell Mom you asked after her. -Please
我和孩子你只能选择其一 妈妈
It's either me or that baby, Mom.
看你怎么选
Your choice.
我想你妈就是在这儿了
I think this must be the place.
我能出来了吗 里面热死了
Can I get out? It's hot in here.
不行
No.
莫妮卡
Monica?
我可以扮演莫妮卡的
I can be if you want me to be.
老天
Jesus!
莫妮卡莫妮卡莫妮卡
Monica? Monica? Monica?
科密特
Kermit?
- 弗兰克 - 你的头是怎么回事
-Frank? -What'd you do to your head?
是我的疗法
Oh, um, my therapy.
对平复神经有好处
It calms my nerves.
你让他们电击你的头了
You let 'em zap your head?
对治我的癫痫病有益
Helps with my seizures.
老天啊
Jesus.
先试试再下定论 弗兰克
Try it before you knock it,Frank.
非常平静
Very restful.
你在这儿见过莫妮卡吗
Have you seen Monica around?
见过 在穿过走廊左拐的地方
Yeah, um... across the hall on your left.
莫妮卡
Monica?
Hey, Monica?
- 弗兰克 - 我来带你出去的
-Frank. -I came to get you out.
我跟你说过了我不想出去
I told you I don't want out.
你干吗停下
Why'd you stop?
你高潮了吗
Did you come?
弗兰克 这是吉尔
Frank, this is Jill.
吉尔 这是我老公 弗兰克
Jill this is my husband, Frank.
妈妈
Mom?
菲奥娜 菲奥娜 快看
Fiona! Fiona, look!
淘气男孩
Boys.
不好意思 我们平常很少放他出门 卡尔
Sorry. We don't let him out of his cage very often. Carl!
快过来
Get over here.
吉姆 你一直在忙活什么呢
So, Jim, what have you been up to?
仍在想方设法地不求上进吗
Still finding new and creative ways to underachieve?
我最近去南美洲玩了一趟
I was traveling around South America till recently.
老爸的痔疮手术还是你执刀的吗
Are you still handling all the hemorrhoidectomies for Dad?
奇普外科实习完后也加入了老爸的诊所
Chip just joined Dad's practice after his surgical residency,
紧紧跟随父亲的脚步
following in the great man's footsteps.
所以你经常会拿刀切人
So you get to cut into people?
太酷了
Awesome.
他带你去滑过雪吗
He take you skiing yet?
还没呢
Uh, no.
我唯一跟雪扯得上关系的天赋就是
My only talent involving snow is
知道如何将过道上的雪铲除
knowing how to shovel the walk
而不打扰到睡在雪窝里的我父亲
without disturbing my father sleeping on it.
而卡尔最拿手的就是在雪地里尿尿
And Carl's pretty good at peeing in it as well.
元旦那天他带去圣莫里茨的那个女孩叫什么名字来着
What was the name of that girl that he took to St. Moritz on New Year's?
克里希 利希 还是什么的
Chrissie? Lizzie?Something.
我记得她的名字是以"希"结尾来着
I remember it had "Ie" On the end of it.
我那年才十七岁
I was 17.
你高中就带女友去欧洲了
You took a girlfriend to Europe in high school?
爸爸赞助的机票
Dad offered a ticket.
他一路把那女孩儿领到了阿尔卑斯山
He drags her all the way to the Alps,
却把人家留在酒店独守空房
then leaves her in the hotel room sitting there
因为他在观光船上又认识了某个法国姑娘
for some French girl he met on the gondola.
奇普 别揪着你弟弟的糗事不放了
Chip, leave your brother alone.
有两件事是可以肯定的
Two things you can count on:
一是我妈对这个小儿子毫不掩饰的偏爱
Mom's naked favoritism for her youngest...
没那回事
That's not true.
我哥还认为我是那个不懂还击的小毛孩
My brother still thinks of me as the runt that didn't punch back.
另一个就是她的小儿子
...and her youngest's quick and stealthy exit
会在弄走她一万块后飞快地偷偷溜走
after he weasels her out of another ten grand.
我这次本打算从她那儿弄走两万
I was hoping to milk her for another 20 this time.
叫奇普的果然都不是什么好东西
With a name like Chip, you'd think you'd want to defy the stereotype.
菲奥娜 别这样 没关系
Fiona, don't. It's fine.
才不是呢
No, it's not.
抱歉来晚了
Well, sorry to be late.
被一个重症病人给耽误了
Whipple on a stage-four patient.
你就是传说中的菲奥娜
So, you are the mysterious Fiona.
这两位是菲奥娜的弟弟 卡尔
And these are Fiona's brothers, Carl...
和伊恩
and Ian...
很高兴认识你 伊恩
Well, nice to meet you, Ian.
我们点好餐了吗
Have we ordered?
不好意思
Excuse me.
去趟洗手间
Bathroom.
- 你的水 先生  - 谢谢
- And your drink, sir. - Thank you.
我得先去洗个手
Ah, you know, I gotta wash my hands.
我要一份生菜沙拉和一份海鲈鱼
I'll have the iceberg lettuce salad and the sea bass.
来一份三分熟的四十八盎司上等双切牛排
Double-cut, 48-ounce prime rib, medium-rare,
和一份两磅的缅因龙虾 谢谢
and the two-pound Maine lobster, please.
他们知道你是同性恋吗
Do they know you're gay?
我不是同性恋
I'm not gay.
是吗 那这算什么呢
Really? What's this then?
想听实话
Honestly?
我这人只要是人就上
Anything that walks, that's me.
天呐 莫妮卡 又搞上一个女人
Jesus, Moni, another lady?
我寂寞如雪
You know, I get lonely.
- 你爱她吗 - 我才认识她
- Do you love her? - I just met her.
你们来这儿干吗
What are you doing here?
我们来帮你逃出去呀
We came to break you out.
我不是跟你说过了吗 我不想出去
I told you, I don't want out.
我想的不得了
Oh, hell, I do.
没人要管你 吉尔
No one's offering, Jill.
你把黛比也拉过来干吗
And why did you have to drag Debbie into this?
如果我一个人来的话 你不会跟我走的
I didn't think you'd come if it was just me.
她怎么被弄进来的
What is she in for?
精神评估 看我能是否上庭受审
Psych evaluation to see if I'm competent to stand trial.
你犯什么事了
What'd you do?
朝我老公开了二十六枪
Shot my husband 26 times.
天呐 你使的什么枪 步枪吗
Jesus, what'd you use, an AK?
手枪
Pistol.
我上了两遍子弹
I reloaded... twice.
莫妮卡 我们希望你在我们身边
Moni, we want you with us.
孩子们需要你
The kids need you.
我需要你
I need you.
痛吗
Does it hurt?
不 我没事
No, I'm okay.
我很抱歉让你目睹那一切 亲爱的
I'm sorry you had to see that, honey.
我只是情绪太低落了
I was just so low, you know?
嗯
Yeah.
但是我现在没事
But I'm okay now.
你们打算怎么把我们弄出去呢
What's this grand plan you have for busting us out?
搞定
Got it.
绳子有点短
That's short.
楼真高
That's a long way down.
我们可以把床单接上去
Could tie sheets to the end.
什么
What?!
这里离屋顶只有两层
Hey, it's only two stories down to the roof...
可以从女厕所过去
outside the ladies' john.
要我去把利亚姆接回来吗
You want me to go pick up Liam?
把他留在V那边过夜也没关系的
Uh, V will be okay keeping him overnight.
那饭店真高级 吉米
Great restaurant, Jimmy.
快看我偷来的这把刀
Check out this cool knife I stole.
那玩意儿必须送回去
That's going back.
他们不介意 反正他们多得是
Hey, they won't miss it. They got tons of 'em.
把刀给我 快去睡觉
Give me that. Bed, now.
谁都不准碰我打包带回来的龙虾
Hey, nobody touch my leftover lobster.
我明早要就着我的肉桂烤华夫饼吃了它
I want to put it in my cinnamon toaster waffle in the morning.
嗨 菲奥娜
Hey, Fiona.
吉米的爸爸罗伊德
Jimmy's dad Loyd,
他...
he, uh..
晚安
Good night.
Night.
干嘛
What?
我爱你
I love you.
你会离开我吗
Are you gonna leave?
不会
No.
每个人最终都离我而去
Everybody always leaves.
我不会的
I won't.
史蒂夫
Steve!
埃斯特法尼亚
Estefania...
- 埃斯特法尼亚- 怎么了
- Estefania.  - What is it?
埃斯特法尼亚冷静点 冷静点
Estefania, hey, calm down, calm down.
到底发生什么了
What the hell happened?
- 嘿 - 马科
- Hey - Marco
等等 这都是马科干的吗 他打你了
Wait. Marco did this to you? He hit you?
马科是不是打你了
Did Marco hit you?
你是我丈夫
You my husband
帮帮我吧
Help me, please?
求你帮帮我
Please help me!
求你了
Please?
你在干吗
What are you doing?
呃 我睡不着 来抽根烟
Uh, I couldn't sleep. Needed a smoke.
你不用到外面来抽
You don't have to do it out here.
爸爸在家的时候 整座房子都能当烟灰缸用
With Dad home, the whole house is an ashtray.
老天 冻死我了
Christ, it's freezing.
因为凯伦吗
Karen?
是吧
Yeah.
我不知道
I don't know.
应该是的 我 我不知道
Maybe. I I don't know.
我真搞不懂你是怎么有了个孩子
I don't get how you have a kid
却完全不关心他的死活
and not give a shit what happens to it.
智障 有两个头
Retarded, two heads,
还是没有脸 不管怎样 都是你的孩子
no face, whatever it's still you.
没有脸?
No face
对啊 呃 说不定他本来是有脸的
Yeah, well, maybe it would have to have a face.
你应该回家
You should go home.
噢 你想赶我走了
Oh, you kicking me out?
赶快回屋里去
Get your ass back in the house
少胡思乱想
and stop thinking so much.
你想再做一次吗
You want to fuck again?
只要几分钟我就可以兴奋了
I'm only gonna be up a couple more minutes.
嘿 伙计
Hey, pal.
嘿 兄弟 伙计
Hey, buddy! Pal!
- 有火吗 - 你什么时候才能把这戒掉
- Got a light? - When are you gonna give those up?
他们会杀了你的
They're gonna kill you.
我知道
I know.
下次我会试试催眠他们的
I'm gonna try hypnosis next.
呃 不 我没有 没有 抱歉
Uh, no, don't. No, sorry.
你的ID卡呢
Where's your I.D. badge?
噢 留在柜子里了
Oh, left it in my locker.
还没到换班的时候呢
Shift's not over.
我把呼吸器
Left my inhaler
忘在车里了
in the car.
我有肺结核和哮喘 挺可怕的
Tuberculosis and asthma. Horrible.
恰克 七号楼有麻烦了
Chuck, we got trouble on seven.
- 精神病房 - 收到
- Psych unit. - Roger that.
任何时候在医院
Got to keep your I.D. badge visible
你都得把你的ID卡带上
at all times on hospital grounds.
黛比
Debbie!
上车
Get in the car.
黛比 到车里去
Debbie, get in the car.
快上车
Get in the car.
小黛比 上车
Debs, get in the car!
上车
Get in the car!
我爱你 黛比
I love you, Debbie!
黛比 我爱你
Debbie, I love you!
她说没有她我们会好过很多的
She said we're better off without her.
这次考试考两个小时
You will have two hours for this exam.
这是多项选择题
This is multiple choice.
如果要改答案的话 一定要把之前的答案擦干净
If you change an answer, be sure to fully erase
并且清楚地标出新的选项
your first answer and clearly circle your second.
我不会
I am not...
我不会读心术
I am not a mind reader.
如果你们不知道答案 继续往下做直到
If you do not know an answer, move on and come back to...
你要去哪里
Where you going?
远离这里的地方
Anywhere far the fuck away from here.
嘿 我今天回学校上学了
Hey, I went back to school today.
参加了物理科的考试
Took the AP Physics final.
你压根儿就没去上过课
You haven't even been going to class.
我几年前看过课本
I read the book a couple years ago.
就是这么回事 妈妈
This is it, Mom.
最后的机会
Last chance.
我不是开玩笑的
I'm not kidding,
我要走了
I'm gone.
是要我还是要孩子
It's me or the baby.
决定吧
Decide.
求你别这么做
Please don't do this.
选我还是选孩子
Me or the baby.
我选孩子 宝贝
The baby, sweetheart.
凯伦
Karen!
知道吗 这么做你会后悔的
You know, you're going to regret this.
哎哟 你说过这些打人不疼的
Ow, ow, ow! I thought you said these things didn't hurt!
我骗你的
I lied.
哎哟 伙计 停下
Ow! Dude, knock it off.
哎哟
Ow!
卡尔和吉米正在客厅玩气枪大战呢
Carl's having an air soft war with Jimmy in the living room.
他们又会把电视屏幕打出个洞的
They're gonna put a dent in the TV screen again.
到外面去打 我已经告诉过你们两次了
Outside! I told you both twice already!
- 火鸡 - 你得习惯它
- Turkey? - Get used to it.
那个和卡尔在莫顿剩下的菜
That and Carl's Morton leftovers
得伴随我们度过接下来的两周
are going to tide us over for the next two weeks.
听着 有些事情我得
Listen, I kind of need to talk
和你谈一谈
to you about something.
不用管她 她一点儿英语也不会
Don't worry about her. She doesn't speak any English.
她现在住在这里
She living here now?
老天啊 我希望不是这样
Good Lord, I hope not.
就是 吉米的爸爸罗伊德
You know, Jimmy's dad Lloyd?
我 呃 我们
I, uh, think we kind of...
噢 上帝啊
Oh, Jesus.
我们没钱 弗兰克
We're broke, Frank.
自从你去年五月把我们的钱都拿走之后
I haven't hidden money in there since you cleaned us out
我就没有在那儿藏过钱了
last May.
钱在哪里
Where is it?
我们没钱
There is no money.
嘿 别动 那些是我的
Whoa! No. Those are mine.
别这样 让他走 伊恩
Come on, let him go, Ian.
不 把它放回去
No, put it back!
你在他妈的跟我开玩笑吗
What, are you fucking kidding me?
嘿 嘿 小心点 放开我
Hey! Hey! Watch it! Get off of me!
- 嘿 停下 - 你在跟我开玩笑吗
- Hey, stop that! - Are you kidding me?!
听着 给我停下
Listen! Fucking stop it!
放开他
Knock it off!
你再敢跟我横 你这个小
Don't you fuck with me! You little...
像马科这样打小孩和女人的贱人都活该被锅打晕
# 夜晚在睡梦中过去 #
The evening sleeps away
# 新的一天来了又去 #
Another day has come and gone
# 灯光充满了灯罩 #
The streetlights soak the shade
# 合成光代替了太阳 #
Synthetic rays replace the sun
# 在你得偿所愿后 #
Conscience soon dying
# 良心即将死去 #
When you get what you want
# 先见稍纵即逝 #
Foresight goes and fades
# 回顾过去 我们就会知道 #
In retrospect, we'll figure out
# 夜晚在睡梦中过去 #
The evening sleeps away
# 想起事后的疑虑 #
Realize the afterthought of doubt
# 最后的几天里 #
Well, these last couple days
# 我们为什么又是怎样到达那里的 #
Been why we're going there and how
利普
Lip!
# 这最后的三天 #
For these three days on end
# 是充满希望的 #
Got to be hopeful
# 这最后的三天 #
These three days on end
# 要站起来 喘口气 #
Got to get up and catch my second wind
# 为它做好准备 #
Got to be up for it.
我不能再做了
I can't again.
我得睡觉
I got to sleep.
孩子们早上要上学
Kids have school in the morning.
我得给黛比的美术作业
I got to find a shoebox for
找一个鞋盒
Debbie's art project.
卡尔还没有做他的拼写作业
Carl hasn't done his spelling.
卡尔的班上要进行义卖
Carl's class is having a bake sale.
我得烤点饼干
I got to I'm gonna make cookies.
饼干 没错
Cookies, right.
还有利亚姆得去诊所
And Liam has to go to the clinic for
为他的下一次
for his next set...
管他的 上来
Screw it, get up here.
# 我们会弄清这些 #
We will know what it's all about
# 今天是 #
And today is the day
利普
Lip?
我好冷
I so cold.
你热不热
You hot?
好吧
Okay.
当然了
Sure.
# 我想说 据我调查 #
And I want to say, as I survey
# 我想把你远远地带走 #
I'd like to take you miles away
# 今天和我一起 #
With me today
# 宝贝 从我这里什么也得不到 #
Sweet lover, got nothing on me
# 你想要 但你不明白 #
You want it, but you can't see
# 你想要 只要说就好 #
You want it, so just say so
# 就一次 如果你肯放手 #
One time, if you just let go
# 宝贝 自由与我无关 #
Baby, freedom's got nothing on me
# 我会给你需要的一切 #
I'll give you everything you need
# 宝贝 给予和拿走是游戏的一部分 #
Baby, give and take is part of the game
# 把它们当成一回事吧 #
Reacting like it's one and the same
# 你以为你会在我这儿找到些什么 #
You thought you'd find something on me
# 慢慢来 你得慢慢来 #
Slow down, you got to slow down.